In the last segment, we explained what is
a public key encryption system. And we
在这一小节中 我们来讲下什么是公钥加密系统
defined what it means for a public key
encryption system to be secure. If you
并且我们来定义下公钥加密系统的安全性
remember, we required security against
active attacks. And in particular, we
如果你还记得的话 我们需要针对主动攻击的安全性
defined chosen cipher text security as our
goal. This week, we're gonna construct two
而且我们要特别定义下选择密文攻击的安全性 这一周
families of public key encryption systems
that are chosen cipher text secure. And in
我们要构建两个具有选择密文攻击安全性的公钥加密系统
this segment, we're gonna start by
constructing public key encryptions from,
并且在这一小节 我们要从陷门置换来
a concept called a trapdoor
permutation. So let's start by defining a
构建一个公钥加密系统 所以我们先来
general concept called a trapdoor
function. So what is a trapdoor function?
定义一下什么是陷门函数
Well, a trapdoor function basically is a
function that goes from some set X to some
一个陷门函数就是一个集合X到集合Y的函数
set Y. And it's really defined by a triple
of algorithms. There's a generation
它是由三个算法定义而成的
algorithm, the function f, and the inverse
of the function f. So the generation
由一个生成算法 一个函数f 一个函数f的逆构成
algorithm, basically what it does when you
run it, it will generate a key pair, a
生成算法就是当你运行它时 会产生一个密钥对
public key and a secret key. The public
key is gonna define a specific function
就是一个公钥和一个私钥 公钥会确定一个特殊的
from the set X to the set Y. And then the
secret key is going to define the inverse
从集合X到集合Y的函数 并且密钥将会确定一个
function now from the set Y to the set
X. So the idea is that you can evaluate
从集合Y到集合X的逆函数 所以你可以用公钥PK来求这个函数值
the function at any point using a public key
PK and then you can invert that function
并且可以用私钥SK来求这个函数的逆
using the secret key, SK. So what do I
mean by inversion? More precisely, if we
那么我说逆的意思是什么呢 详细来说就是
look at any public key and secret key pair
generated by the key generation algorithm
如果我们看到密钥生成算法生成的任何密钥对
G, then it so happens that if I evaluate
the function at the point X, and then I
假如我求得了在点X的函数值
evaluate the inverse at the resulting
point, I should get the original point X
然后我想要求这个点的值的逆 我就可以得到原始的X的值
back. So the picture you should have in
your mind, is there is this big set X and
你们可以想象下 有一个大集合X和一个大集合Y
this big set Y And then, this function
will map any point in X to a point in Y,
这个函数从X中的一些点映射到Y中的一个点
and this can be done using the public key.
So again any point in X can be mapped, to
并且都这是用公钥来实现的 所以X中的点可以映射
a point in Y. And then if someone has the
secret key, then basically they can go in
Y中的点 那么如果有人拥有这个私钥 那么他们就可以
the reverse direction by applying, this
secret key sk. So now that we
用SK来颠倒这个过程 那么现在
understand what a trapdoor function is,
let's define what it means for a trapdoor
我们已经理解了陷门函数的意思 我们再来定义下
function to be secure. And so we'll say
that this triple, (G, F, F inverse), is secure
陷门函数的安全性 我们可以说 这三个函数(G,F,F的逆)
if in fact this function F(PK, .) is what's
called a one way function. And let me
他们整体是单向函数的话就是安全的
explain what a, what is a one way
function. The idea is that basically the
我来解释下什么是单向函数 就是说一个函数在
function can be evaluated at any point,
but inverting it is difficult without the
任意一点可以求值 但是如果没有私钥的话就难以求得它的逆函数
secret key SK. So let's define that more
precisely. As usual we define that using a
那么我们再用一个比赛来详细定义下吧
game. So here we have our game between the
challenger and the adversary. And the game
这里我们有一个挑战者和敌手之间的比赛
proceeds as follows. Basically the
challenger will generate a public key and
挑战者先生成一个公钥和一个私钥
a secret key. And then they will generate
a random X. It will send the public key
然后他们会生成一个随机数X 然后把公钥发送给敌方
over to the adversary and then it will
evaluate the function at the point X and
然后用公钥会求得这个函数在点X的值Y
send the resulting Y also to the
adversary. So all the adversary gets to
并将其发送给敌方 那么敌方的到的就
see is just a public key, which defines
what the function is, and then he gets to
仅仅是一个定义了这个函数的公钥
see the image of this function on a random
point X and is goal is basically to invert
然后他得看下这个函数在点X的值
the function at this point Y. Okay, so he
outputs some X prime. And we said that the
并且用Y求这个函数的逆 那么他就可以得到X的值了
trap door function is secure if the
probability that the ad, adversary inverts
前面我们说过 如果对手可以用Y求得这个函数的逆的概率非常小的话
the given at point y is negligible. In
other words, given y the probability that
那这个陷门函数就是安全的 就是说 通过给定Y
the adversary's able to alter the pre
image of y is in fact a negligible
无论使用那种算法
probability and if that's true for all
efficient algorithms then we say that this
来求得它的原象的概率非常低的话
trapdor function is secure. So again
abstractly, it's a really interesting
那么这个陷门函数就是安全的 这是一个很有趣的概念
concept in that you can evaluate the
function in the forward direction very
你可以非常简单从一个方向求得这个函数
easily. But then no one can evaluate the
function in the reverse direction unless
但是没人能从另一个方向求得这个陷门函数
they have this trapdoor, the secret key
SK, which then all of a sudden lets them
如果没有私钥SK的话 但是私钥SK可以让求逆变得非常
invert the function very, very easily. So
using the concept of a trapdoor function,
非常的简单 所以 通过使用陷门函数
it's not too difficult to build a public key encryption system, and let me show you how
建立一个公钥加密系统就不难了 我们来看看怎么做
to do it. So here we have we our trap door
function, (G, F, and F inverse). The other
这里我们有一个陷门函数(G,F,F的逆)
tool that we are going to need is a symmetric encryption scheme, and I'm going to
另一个我们需要的工具就是对称加密体制
assume that this encryption scheme is actually
secure against active attacks, so in
我们先假设这个加密体制面对主动攻击是安全的
particular I needed to provide
authenticated encryption. Notice that the
那么 我需要一个认证加密技术
symmetric encryption system takes keys in
K and the trapdoor function takes inputs
注意一下 对称加密系统用密钥来加密K 陷门函数用输入来加密X
in X. Those are two different sets and so
we're also gonna need the hash function.
有两个不同的集合 同时我们也需要一个从X映射到K的
That goes from X to K. In other words, it
maps elements in the set X into keys for
杂凑函数 换句话说 就是它把集合X中的元素映射到对称加密系统的密钥中
the symmetric encryption systems. And now
once we have these three components, we
现在我们有了这三个部分
can actually construct the public key encryption system as follows: so the key
我们就可以构建一个这样的公钥加密系统
generation for the public key encryption
system is basically exactly the same as
公钥加密系统中的密钥生成器和陷门函数中的
the key generation for the trap door
function. So we run G for the trap door
密钥生成器一样 那么我们运行陷门函数中的G函数
function, we get a public key and a secret
key. And those are gonna be the public and
得到一个公钥私钥对 并且这将会作为公钥加密系统的
secret keys for the public key encryption
system. And how do we encrypt and decrypt? Let's
公钥和私钥 那么我们如果来加密和解密呢
start with encryption. So the encryption
algorithm takes a public key and a message
我们先从加密说起 加密算法需要一个公钥和一个消息作为输入
as input. So what it will do is it will
generate a random X from the set capital
然后它会从集合X中生成一个随机数X
X. It will then apply the trapdoor
function to this random X, to obtain Y. So
然后把X代入到陷门函数中 生成Y
Y is the image of X under the trapdoor
function. Then it will go ahead and
那么Y就是X在陷门函数下的映射
generate a symmetric key by hashing X. So
this is a symmetric key for the symmetric
然后它会把X代入杂凑函数来产生一个对称密钥 即对称密钥系统的
key system. And then finally it encrypts
the plain text message 'm' using this key that was
对称密钥 然后最终 它用这个密钥来加密明文消息M
just generated. And then it outputs the
value Y that it just computed, which is
然后它就会输出Y的值 也就是X的映射
the image of X, along the encryption under
the symmetric system of the message M. So
在加密对称加密系统中的消息M时
that's how encryption works. And I want to
emphasize again that the trapdoor function
这就是加密过程如何工作的 我要再一次强调的是陷门函数
is only applied to this random value X,
whereas the message itself is encrypted
仅仅是适用于这个随机值X 而这个消息本身是
using a symmetric key system using a key
that was derived from the value X that we
用一个来自我们随机选择的X的值的秘钥加密的对称加密系统
chose at random. So now that we understand
encryption, let's see how to decrypt.
加密的 因此我们明白了加密过程 现在来看如何解密
While the decryption algorithm takes a
secret key as input, and the ciphertext.
当解密算法使用一个私钥和密文作为输入
The ciphertext itself contains two
components, the value Y and the value C.
密文本身包含两个部分 y值和c值
So the first step we're gonna do, is we're
gonna apply the inverse transformation,
所以第一步我们要做的是 我们要使用逆变换
the inverse trap door function to the
value Y, and that will give us back the
对y值使用逆陷门函数 那会让我们得到
original X that was chosen during
encryption. So now let me ask you, how do
加密时最原始的x的值 那么 我们怎么
we derive the symmetric decryption key K
from this X that we just obtained? Well,
从我们刚得到的x推导出对称解密密钥k
so that's an easy question. We basically
hash X again. That gives us K just as
这个问题很简单 我们再次HASH x 得到
during encryption. And now that we have
this symmetric encryption key we can apply
加密时的那个k 现在我们有对称加密密钥 我们可以
the, the symmetric decryption algorithm to
decrypt the ciphertext C. We get the
对应这个对称解密密钥到解密密文c 我们得到
original message M and that's what we
output. So, that's how the public key
原始消息m 这就是我们得到的输出 这就是公钥
encryption system works were this trap
door function is only used for encrypting
加密系统的工作过程 这个陷门函数只是用于加密
some sort of a random value X and the
actual message is encrypted using the
一些随机值x 真正的消息是用对称系统
symmetric system. So in pictures here, we
have the message M obviously the plain
加密的 在这张图片里 我们有消息m 显然
text could be quite large. So, here we
have the body of the deciphered text which
纯文本的可能会相当大 这里我们有解密文本的内容
can be quite long is actually encrypted
using the symmetric system. And then again
这会有相当长的一部分是用对称系统加密的 再次强调
I emphasize that the key for the
symmetric system is simply the hash of X.
对称系统的密钥仅仅是对x的HASH的函数
And then the header of ciphertext is simply
this application of the trapdoor
密文的开头仅仅是陷门函数对
function to this random X that we picked.
And so during decryption what happens is
我们得到的随机值x的应用 在解密期间会发生的是
we first decrypt the header to get X and
then we decrypt the body using the
我们首先解密开头以得到x 然后用
symmetric system to actually get the
original plain text M. So as usual when I
对称系统解密消息体以得到原始明文消息m 像往常一样
show you a system like this, obviously you
want to verify that decryption in fact is
我为你们介绍一个类似的系统 显然你们想验证这个解密过程其实是
the inverse of encryption. But more
importantly you want to ask why is this
加密过程的逆运算 但是更重要的是这个系统的安全性
system secure. And in fact there's a nice
security theorem here that says. That if
其实这里有一个好的安全定理 就是
the trap door function that we started
with is secure. In other words, that's a
如果我们使用的陷门函数安全 换句话说
one way function if the adversary doesn't
have a secret key. The symmetric
有一个单向函数 如果对手没有密钥 对称
encryption system provides authenticated
encryption. And the hash function is a
加密系统提供身份验证的加密 HASH函数是一个
random oracle, which simply means that
it's a random function from the set X to
随机预言 它仅仅意味着它是来自集合x到密钥集k的
the set of keys K. So a random oracle is
some sort of an idealization of, what a
随机函数 所以一个随机预言是某种理想化的函数
hash function is supposed to be. In
practice, of course, when you come to
跟HASH函数应该很像 当然在实践中 当你去
implement a system like this, you would
just use, SHA-256, or any of the
实现这样一个系统的时候 你可能会用SHA-256，或者其他
other hash functions that we discussed in
class. So, under those three conditions in
任何我们在课堂上讲过的HASH函数 所以 在那三种情况下
fact the system that we just described is
chosen cipher text secure so it is CCA
事实上我们刚才讨论的系统是选择密文安全的 所以它是CCA安全的
secure, the little ro here just denote the
fact that security is set in whats called
这个随机预言只表示了随机预言模型中的集合的安全性
a random oracle model. But, that's a detail
that's actually not so important for
但是 这里还有一个不太重要的细节
discussion here, what I want you to
remember is that if the trap door function
你们要记住的是 如果陷门函数
is in fact a secure trap door function. The
symmetric encryption system is secure
是一个安全的陷门函数 对称加密系统
against tampering so it provides
authenticated encryption. And H
对应于篡改是安全的 则它提供经过身份验证的加密
is in some sense a good hash function.
It's a random, function, which in practice
h在某种程度上是一个好HASH函数 那个练习中的随机函数
you would just use SHA-256, then in
fact the system that we just showed is CCA
你们只用SHA-256 其实我们刚才讲的系统是
secure, is chosen ciphertext secure. I should
tell you that there's actually an ISO
CCA安全的 是选择密文安全的 我要告诉你们 其实有
standard that, defines this mode of
encryption, of public encryption. ISO
ISO标准 定义了这种加密 称为公开加密
stands for International Standards
Organization. So in fact this particular
ISO标准化组织 所以其实这个特殊的
system has actually been standardized, and
this is a fine thing to use. I'll refer to
系统事实上被标准化了 这用起来是个好东西 我要提一下这个
this as the ISO encryption in the next few
segments. To conclude this segment, I want
作为下面几节课的ISO加密 总结下这一节课
to warn you about an incorrect way of
using a trapdoor function to build a
我要警告你们关于一个使用陷门函数去建立
public key encryption system. And in fact
this method might be the first thing that
公钥加密系统的错误点 其实这个方法可能是第一个
comes to mind, and yet it's completely
insecure. So let me show you, how not to
能想到的 目前它是完全不安全的 我来讲解下怎样才能
encrypt using a trapdoor function. Well
the first thing that might come to mind
不用陷门函数加密 第一件事我们能想到的是
is, well, let's apply the trapdoor
function directly to the message M. So we
我们直接对这个消息m应用陷门函数 所以我们
encrypt simply by applying a function to
the message M, and we decrypt simply by
仅仅使用函数计算去加密消息m 那我们解密也仅仅是
applying F inverse to the ciphertext C to
recover the original message M. So
使用f对密文c求逆去恢复原始消息m
functionally, this is in fact, decryption
is the inverse of encryption, and yet this
这个其实函数的解密就是对加密的逆运算 目前
is completely insecure for many, many
different reasons. The easiest way to see
这有很多很多理由不安全 最简单的方法去看
that this is insecure, is that it's
simply, this is deterministic encryption.
这个不安全因素 就是它太简单 它是确定加密
You notice there is no randomness being
used here. When we encrypt a message
你会注意到这里没有用到随机性 当我们加密一个消息m
M, and since it is
deterministic, it's cannot possibly be
由于它是确定的 就不可能
semantically secure. But in fact, as I
said, when we instantiate this trap door
在语义上是安全的 但其实如我所说 当我们用特定的实现
function with particular implementations,
for example with the RSA trap door
去实例化这个陷门函数 以这个RSA陷门函数为例
function, then there are many, many
attacks that are possible on this
有很多很多可能的攻击
particular construction, and so you should
never, ever, ever use it, and I'm gonna
对这个特定的结构 所以你们以后千万不要用它 我要
repeat this throughout this module, and in
fact in the next segment I'll show you a
在这个模块多次重复这个 其实在下一节课 我会给你们
number of attacks on this particular
implementation. Okay so, what I would like
讲一些对这个特定实现的攻击 好 我希望你们记住
you to remember is that you should be
using an encryption system like the ISO
你们要按照ISO标准去应用加密系统
standard, and you should never apply the
trap door function directly to the message M.
永远不要直接将陷门函数应用于消息m
Although in the next segment we'll
see other ways to encrypt using a trap
即使下一节课我们会学习使用陷门函数加密的其他方法
door function that are also correct, but
this particular method is clearly, clearly
那些是正确的 但是这个特定的模型是明显
incorrect. Okay, so now that we understand
how to build public key encryption
明显不正确的 好 现在我们明白了如何使用给定的陷门函数
given a trap door function, the next
question is how to construct trap door
建立公钥加密 下一个问题就是如何建立
functions, and we're going to do that in
the next segment.
陷门函数 我们下节课再讲